Guide to the Homer L. Bartlett Medieval Manuscript Fragments MSS.535
Fales Library and Special Collections
Homer L. Bartlett Medieval Manuscript Fragments
0990-1980
Fales Library and Special Collections
Bartlett, Homer L., 1858-
MSS.535
2.75 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box.
Homer Lewis Bartlett was a graduate of New York University at the University Heights campus. This collection consists of medieval and Renaissance fragments collected by Bartlett. This collection consists of manuscript fragments from the 10th through 18th centuries, the majority of which are in Latin and Biblical in nature. The collection also includes a small number of theological Greek fragments from the 13th through 15th centuries, 14th and 15th century fragments in Latin about music, a table of contents for a treatise on minerals and herbs, and the will of Joan Girard.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of medieval and Renaissance fragments collected by Homer L. Bartlett. This collection consists of manuscript fragments from the 10th through 18th centuries, the majority of which are in Latin and Biblical in nature. The collection also includes a small number of theological Greek fragments from the 13th through 15th centuries, 14th and 15th century fragments in Latin about music, an English-language table of contents for a treatise on minerals and herbs, and the will of Joan Girard.
Custodial History
The original provenance of these fragments is unknown. Homer Lewis Barlett, a graduate of New York University Heights, donated the manuscript fragments to the Heights Library in 1884. The items were transferred to the New York University Archives at some point after the sale of the Heights campus. In 1978 Bayrd Still, Director of the Archives Office transferred the manuscript fragments to the Fales Library.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical Note
Homer Lewis Bartlett was a graduate of New York University at the University Heights campus.
Other Finding Aids
Materials in this collection are described on the item-level in Digital Scriptorium: http://www.digital-scriptorium.org/xtf3/search?rmode=digscript&smode=bid&bid=25&docsPerPage=30. Where applicable, items have notes containing a direct link to the Digital Scriptorium.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Original order is unknown.
Manuscripts (documents); Manuscripts, Medieval
- Item Numbers Identified, circa mid-20th century (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fragment 001, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Language: Latin
  Country of Origin: England
  Other Finding Aids
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment001_25
- Fragment 002, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment002_25
- Fragment 003, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment003_25
- Fragment 004, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment004_25
- Fragment 005, 1100-1199 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment005_25
- Fragment 006, 1573 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Language: English
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment006_25
- Fragment 007, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment007_25
- Fragment 008 and Fragment 009, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Country of Origin: Italy
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment008andFragment009_25
- Fragment 010, 1437 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment010_25
- Fragment 011, 1260-1299 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment011_25
- Fragment 012, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment012_25
- Fragment 013, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment013_25
- Fragment 014, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment014_25
- Fragment 015, 1568 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment015_25
- Fragment 016 and Fragment 017, 1300-1499 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment016_25 and http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment017_25
- Fragment 018, 1438 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment018_25
- Fragment 019, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment019_25
- Fragment 020, 1414 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment020_25
- Fragment 021, 1500-1550 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment021_25
- Fragment 022, 1482 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment022_25
- Fragment 023, 1200-1250 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Country of Origin: France
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment023_25
- Fragment 024, 1150-1199 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment024_25
- Fragment 025, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment025_25
- Fragment 026, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment026_25
- Fragment 027, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment027_25
- Fragment 028, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment028_25
- Fragment 029, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment029_25
- Fragment 030, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment030_25
- Fragment 031, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment031_25
- Fragment 032 and Fragment 033, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment032033034035_25
- Fragment 034 and Fragment 035, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Fragment 036, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment036_25
- Fragment 037, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment037_25
- Fragment 038, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Fragment 040, 1100-1199 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment040_25
- Fragment 041, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Fragment 042 and Fragment 043, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment042andFragment043_25
- Fragment 044, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment044_25
- Fragment 045, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Fragment 046 and Fragment 047, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Fragment 048, 1100-1199 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment048_25
- Fragment 049, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment049_25
- Fragment 050, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment050_25
- Fragment 051, 1250-1275 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment051_25
- Fragment 052, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment052_25
- Fragment 053, 1300-1399 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment053_25
- Fragment 054, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment054_25
- Fragment 055, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment055_25
- Fragment 056, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment056_25
- Fragment 057, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment057_25
- Fragment 058, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment058_25
- Fragment 059, 1450-1499 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment059_25
- Fragment 060, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment60_25
- Fragment 061 and Fragment 062, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment061andFragment062_25
- Fragment 063 and Fragment 064, 1450-1499 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment063064065066_25
- Fragment 065 and Fragment 066, 1450-1499 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Fragment 067, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment067_25
- Fragment 068, 1200-1299 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment068_25
- Fragment 069, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment069andFragment070_25
- Fragment 070, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Fragment 071, 1275-1299 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment071_25
- Fragment 072, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Fragment 073, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Fragment 074, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Fragment 075 and Fragment 076, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Fragment 077, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Fragment 078, circa 990-1800 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Fragment 079 and Fragment 080, 1400-1499 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment079andFragment080_25
- Fragment 081, 1300-1399 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment081_25
- Fragment 082, 1300-1399 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment082_25
- Fragment 083, 1400-1499 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment083_25
- Fragment 084, 1400-1499 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment084andFragment085_25
- Fragment 085, 1400-1499 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Fragment 086, 1400-1499 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment086_25
- Fragment 087, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Fragment 088 and Fragment 089, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Fragment 090, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fragment 091, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Fragment 092 and Fragment 093, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fragment 094 and Fragment 095, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Fragment 096, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Fragment 097, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Fragment 098, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Fragment 099, 1450-1475 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Language: Middle English
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment099_25
- Fragment 100, 1400-1499 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment100_25
- Fragment 101, circa 990-1800 (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 1)
- Fragment 102, circa 990-1800 (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 2)
- Fragment 103, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Fragment 104, 1440-1460 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment104_25
- Fragment 105, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Fragment 106, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Fragment 107, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Fragment 108, 1509 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Language: Latin, Middle French
  Additional descriptive information is available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment108_25
- Fragment 109, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Fragment 110, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Fragment 111, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Fragment 112, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Fragment 113, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Fragment 114, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Fragment 115, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Fragment 116, 1000-1099 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Language: Ancient Greek
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment116_25
- Fragment 117, 990-1010 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Additional descriptive information and digital surrogates are available at: http://ds.lib.berkeley.edu/Fragment117_25
- Fragment 175, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Loose in Album, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Paper Document 1, circa 990-1800 (Box Shared Fales 039, Folder 3)
- Paper Document 2, circa 990-1800 (Box Shared Fales 039, Folder 4)
- Paper Document 3, circa 990-1800 (Flat-file-folder x)
- Paper Document 4, circa 990-1800 (Flat-file-folder x)
- Binding, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Album--10 Fragments, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- French Fragments, 1754-1761 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Greek Fragments, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Fragment 176, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Fragment 177, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Fragment 178, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Fragment 179, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Fragment 180, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Fragment 181, circa 990-1800 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Fragment 182, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Fragment 183, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Fragment 184, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Fragment 185, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Fragment 186, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Fragment 187, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Fragment 188, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fragment 189, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Fragment 190, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Fragment 191, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Fragment 192, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fragment 193, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Fragment 194, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Fragment 195, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Fragment 196, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Fragment 197, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Fragment 198, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Fragment 199, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Fragment 200, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Fragment 201, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Fragment 202, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Fragment 203, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Fragment 204, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Fragment 205, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Fragment 206, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Fragment 207, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Fragment 208, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Latin, Cicero. Oration pro A. Cluentio Sections 96 on.
- Fragment 209, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Fragment 210, circa 990-1800 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Music
- Fragment 211, 16th century (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 3)
- Fragment 212, 16th century (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 4)
- Fragment 213, 16th century (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 5)
- Fragment 214, 16th century (Box Shared Fales 040, Folder 6)
- Fragment 215, 16th century (Box 3, Folder 33)